Runbo Zhang

Blackrock, Co. Dublin | 083 198 0291 | runbo.zhang19@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/runb

PROFILE

Motivated and versatile engineering professional with a distinctive blend of expertise and exceptional academic records in Material Science (MEng, Imperial College) and Business Analytics (MSc, UCD Smurfit). Keen to use my unique multidisciplinary and multicultural background to drive innovation. Proactively acquired analytical skills and experience in multiple industries, including patent reviewing, robotics, and tutoring. 5 years of experience in Python.

EDUCATION

MSc in Business Analytics, UCD Smurfit Graduate Business School, Dublin, Ireland

2023 - 2024

- Grade/Expected Grade: First Class Honours.
- Key modules: Data Management, Technology Consulting, Decision Analytics and Support System, Statistics.
- Project:

Capstone research project (Upcoming): Work in close collaboration with an analytics employer.

MEng in Material Science and Engineering, Imperial College London, London, United Kingdom

2019 - 2023

- Grade: First Class Honours.
- Key modules: Bio- and Nano-materials, Mathematics, Computing and Simulation, Physics and Chemistry.
- Project MEng individual research project:

Optical 3D Printing of a Tissue Engineering Hydrogel: Solved the 3D printing issue of a tissue engineering hydrogel during experiment, proposed a heuristic reaction-diffusion differential equation and simulated using Python. Gained experience in soft gel synthesis and 3D printing, enhanced skills in critical reviewing, planning, experiment constructing, data processing, analysis, and thesis writing.

CAREER EXPERIENCE

Tutor (Part-time), Shanghai Daobi Edutech Ltd, Beijing

Jun 2022 - Present

Online tutorial/educational platform for third-level (university) students.

- Created mind maps, revision sheets, slides, and quizzes to help STEM students understand their courses (including mathematics, material chemistry, crystallography, mineralogy, and MATLAB simulation).
- Helped 3 fail-grade students pass their courses or exams. Enhanced my skills in writing, teaching and MS Office.

Patent and Business Analyst (Part-time), Jucreate Internet Technology Ltd, Beijing

Jul 2022 - Oct 2022

Industrial analysing and technology-enterprise rating company, provides an information hub to stakeholders.

- Reviewed material technology patents and relevant scientific journals, analysed enterprises' information.
- Rated 50+ enterprises focusing on their technical innovation and business capabilities, written in detailed reports.
 Gained knowledge of the status quo of the materials industry in China.

Material Engineer (Self-employed), Beijing Tuling Microelectronics Ltd (Joybeing), Beijing

Jan 2022
Al cooking robotics and vending machine start-up.

Jan 2022 - Aug 2022

- Improved material selection and design for a cooking robot, responsible for public speaking and communication with potential customers and investors, and coordinated a multilingual R&D team.
- Gave interviews and helped in building a good profile for the company during the World Robot Conference 2022.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- IT Skills: Microsoft Office, Python and Machine Learning, Solidworks, COMSOL, Mosel, HTML, Linux.
- Languages: Chinese (Native), English (Fluent).

OTHER INFORMATION

- Awards: AstraZeneca Sustainability Hackathon 2020 Team Silver Award (As a python programmer, in a team of 4, proposed a commercial operation to help better recycling of medical wastes, built a demo garbage classifier neuron network and UI, gained the experience of teamwork and collaborative programming).
- Interests: Creating mathematics, biomaterial, nanomaterial, quantum mechanics and other science content videos and articles on Chinese social media.